Ronny Haase



2 Berlin, Germany

On request On request

I'm developing web based solutions for more than 10 years with focus but not limited to front-end development. I offer excellent knowledge and multiple years of experience with designing, developing, testing and optimizing scalable web solutions.

I've been working with companies and agile teams of different size and experience, and also took leadership responsibilities, was holding presentations and giving trainings on front-end topics either general or for concrete projects.

Key Skills

JavaScript NodeJS	CSS 3 HTML 5	ReactJS	jQuery	AngularJS	BackboneJS	HTTP
REST / RESTful APIs	Unit Tests Integration	on Tests	E2E Tests	TypeScript	CoffeeScript	Git
DevOps Cloud Computing PHP Java Ruby Web / Micro Services NoSQL						
Relational Databases Agile Methodologies / SCRUM						

Work Experience

07/2016 - 12/2016 Zalando SE

Berlin, Germany

Frontend Software-Engineer

- Test-driven full-stack development in agile team
- Front-end development: Universal web apps with ReactJS & Redux
- Back-end development: Multiple micro-services with NodeJS (ExpressJS & HapiJS)
- All systems running live and in production on AWS using CD & CI

11/2013 - 06/2016 StayFriends GmbH

Berlin, Germany

Frontend Developer

- Worked in multiple agile cross-functional teams, partly in leading role
- Lead & developed refactoring SPAs for member area with AngularJS

- Training the whole engineering department on AngularJS, JavaScript, front-end engineering & architecture
- Renewed performance critical, SEO optimized public pages using Progressive Enhancement
- Partly also back-end development with Java & JSP on Tomcat

07/2013 – 10/2013 Freelancer

Germany

Frontend Developer / Web Application Developer & -Architect

Beside parental leave supported multiple smaller projects of the government with my front-end knowledge:

- Coaching about and improving responsive and adaptive web solutions
- Improved responsiveness of an official city page
- Implemented front-end for Cordova based city guide app

07/2012 - 06/2013

the a-team GmbH

Berlin, Germany

Frontend Developer

- Built solutions for core-product used by leading multinational tourism companies using jQuery, Bootstrap and BackboneJS
- Introduced more modern front-end architecture, libraries & tools and service oriented architecture
- · Also back-end development with PHP and DevOps

09/2011 - 06/2012

Freelancer

Germany

Frontend Developer // Web Application Developer & -Architect

During this freelancing period I developed the front-end part for a web application for online reviewing catalogues and special offer flyers for one of Germanys biggest chain of drug stores, in close cooperation with another company taking care of the back-end.

08/2004 – 08/2011 Freelancer (as a side job)
--

Berlin, Germany

Web Developer & -Designer

01/2004 - 06/2004

BBJ Servis gGmbH

Berlin, Germany

Software- & Database-Developer

09/2000 - 08/2003

Devcon Software GmbH

Berlin, Germany

Trainee as "IT Specialist, Application Development"

Publications

11/2011

"PopcornJS - Das HTML5-Media-Framework"

Webstandards magazine issue 12/2011 - 2 pages

Education

10/2009 - 09/2011	Humboldt University of Berlin	Berlin, Germany
	Study of Computer Science	
08/2004 - 06/2008	Treptow-Kolleg	Berlin, Germany
	A-Level / Abitur	
09/2000 - 08/2003	Devcon Software GmbH	Berlin, Germany
	Trainee as "IT Specialist, Application Development"	

Others / Voluntary Activities

12/2009 - 06/2011	Recreational activities on weekends for groups of children with disability
06/2009 - 06/2013	Case work of child with disability
09/2008 - 05/2009	Civilian service at Helene-Häusler-Schule, special school

Interests & Skills

Languages	German	Native language

Englisch Fluent

Hobbies & Interests Music, Photography, Design, Technology

Berlin, 07.08.2017